如果你用中文可以幫他翻譯?
什麼?
OK, so yeah, use English, but if you have...
My Chinese is terrible. One of these people will try to translate.
Any questions?
有沒有我剛剛對,就是,第一個講到的東西有問題?
我想請問一下就是
我看你們的遊戲是需要16個人玩的
那因為要16個人
16個人同時玩你們遊戲
那你們線上人數應該是要蠻多的
你們是怎麼樣保持就是
一直線上一直有人
或者是就是這個狀況
所以
What we do is, we use Photon right now.
Photon are online multiplayer game servers.
And, Photon, they're built for scalability.
So, whether you have one or two people playing or...
Sorry, Dylan, I think he was asking sort of about community engagement problem,
it's not technical problem.
Oh, community engagement problem.
How did you kickstart this community at first?
How did you get the first 100 people, first 200 people in?
Okay, so this was a big challenge.
This is a really good question.
So, you have to market where you can
and try to pull people in through one central hub.
In our case, we use Discord.
Later on, we'll throw them to different places like Facebook, and Forum, and Reddit, and
all that stuff.
But early, you want to concentrate on one hub, because you don't want people watering
out to different hubs.
So if you don't use Discord, you can use anything else.
You can use a forum or something.
Anything as long as it's one place where people can live chat.
or at least post really easily.
So we put links everywhere, doing everything.
So when we have YouTube, we have YouTube videos playing.
I'll do like devlogs or something, where I'll say,
hey, I'm going to give you two minutes to show
what I've been doing, what I've been developing,
sort of like a video blog.
And underneath, I'll put the link, join our Discord.
And I'll post.
I'll post in a forum and I'll say, join our Discord.
I'll put my signature, join our Discord.
So everything is all about rallying people
to this one place.
And so we have, at the beginning,
we had the one page website that just had the email form,
email signups.
So when we sent out the email, we would also say,
at the bottom and top of every email, join our Discord.
So we're sort of bugging people, but it works.
and we really want to push them to this one central place.
And so when we had our alpha, we only
had an average of zero people online.
So it was pretty embarrassing.
And since we need 16 people to play, or 16 people
is the most fun.
Eight you can play, but it's like if you
played an MMO by yourself.
It's not very fun.
But even then, what I did was, when people were in Discord,
I made a bot that would detect when people would play.
And whenever someone would make a game,
it would announce to everyone, the robot,
the bot would say, hey everyone,
this person just made a game, everyone should join.
And if you use Steam, you can have a link.
You know those links that you can click on
and it goes to an application instead of a website?
We used one of those.
You say, hey, everyone, click here to join him.
If you have the game.
So when you click it, it would launch the game.
So they wouldn't even have to look for the game.
They just need to click the link, and it'll
launch the game for them.
And that really helped, too.
And then at the end, it would say,
the bot would give a summary and tell everyone else
to join the second game.
And so the bot would sort of help people get together,
and it would sort of ping them if you're here, too.
We have a rank you can join.
If you join this rank, you'll be pinged
whenever someone gets online.
So yeah, it was very, very difficult.
But you've got to try everything to get people rallied.
It's a lot of work at the beginning.
Do you think doing a Kickstarter campaign sort of helped you get this initial mass of people?
No. Kickstarter didn't help as much as we thought. It really did not help as much as we thought.
So we were a bit disappointed for the results when it comes to being covered by media or getting extra people to join.
I don't think it did that much, to be honest.
You may want to invest time and resources into just doing other things for marketing and getting the community together
whatever you can whatever you can do, but
What our secret was just getting in people little by little so when I said earlier market early
I mean literally two years later
That's when we finally started to have a bunch of people
Just a little bit out of time one person would join per day, and then maybe three people will join per day
And it's very slow.
But you still, even when you have just a few people,
you need to talk to them.
Because as indie developers, this
is something that we can do that AAA developers cannot do.
We can talk to the community.
And they think that is awesome.
That's what gets them to stay.
That you can participate directly with the community.
That if you have an alpha or beta,
maybe you can play with them sometimes.
他們會告訴其他人,哇,這個社群好酷,你們應該加入,甚至開發者會跟你們說話
這對我們有很大的幫助
然後你就必須要先準備
然後Kickstarter的人喔
我發現就是會給我們
一百塊一百五甚至五百塊美金的那些人
其實他們根本不玩遊戲
所以我之後我們有一大堆名單
但是我一直寄email給他們
可是他們就是完全不玩遊戲的人
所以Kickstarter的族群跟遊戲
跟有玩家的族群是不一樣
然後你去跟玩家講說
拜託來贊助我們一下
可是他們不一定會來
因為他們就是要花小錢玩遊戲的人
所以他們其實基本上不會幫助你募資
所以我們就發現說募資並沒有真的幫助我們在用戶
就是真的遊戲玩家上面
那真的幫助我們可能是封測Alpha和Beta
我們在Alpha的時候真的很struggle
他真的每天晚上想說
天啊 明天如果只有七個人怎麼辦
然後可能我們
因為我們的粉絲就是散佈在世界各地
然後就是終於有七個人了
然後沒有 就是終於第八個人加入了
然後結果這個人去睡覺了
然後所以又只好再繼續等
然後之後我就說
請我們的那個設計師
就是我們的2D Artist
我想說拜託你玩一下好不好
特惠人數也好
所以
Alpha就是真的很重要
那個時間會慢慢幫助你
就是持續成長
不要等到最後一刻才發現
我是多人的
我需要人來支持我
Discord was already open. During our Kickstarter, we used Discord as the main thing to rally people, because we have instant access to them.
How many people were on Discord and how many were on Steam?
Oh, during Alpha? We still had a decent amount of people during Alpha, but not that many.
I think we had about 2,000 people during Alpha.
But just on Discord.
But it doesn't mean they're online.
It just means that they're there.
The browser is open.
It's open somewhere.
And they may be in a different server.
Because you can have different servers.
It's like you're in Steam.
It doesn't mean you're playing one specific game.
Or maybe you're not even there.
When the game is released, how do you prepare for it?
Our beta started, when we released the beta,
it started getting more popular.
And then the streamers started to come in more.
So that really helped us prepare for our release more.
Because there were actually players.
So there was always at least one full game going.
One or two games going always.
So that helped.
So then when we launched, we really rallied everyone
way ahead of time.
We kept counting down.
So we'll say, oh, 30 days, 29 days, 28 days.
Everyone's probably bugged at us by then, but it really sort of got put in their mind.
So that everyone joined that one day.
And when we launched, we got everyone to stream the game at the same time on Twitch.
And so suddenly, it got really popular on Twitch.
And we also got lucky and had a famous Twitch streamer named Lyric play our game.
And so we didn't even know he played it, but suddenly there's a huge burst of people.
And it was because this Twitch guy was streaming.
So that really helped our initial population.
Be sure to talk to Twitch streamers
and hand them free keys.
And they will play your game.
I mean, you handed them free keys,
and you give them extra keys to give away.
Because if you just give them one, you know, it's sort of cool.
You got a free game.
But I'm sure they get free games all the time.
給他們四個鑰匙,然後他們會有三個鑰匙,可能給一個朋友,或是兩個給別人
所以Twitch的直播者想要有一個交流,所以你給他們一些東西,讓他們可以和觀眾交流,他們就更有可能會玩你的遊戲
我覺得Twitch幫了我們很多
我們一開始的時候,US的玩家比較多,然後就常常會有EU的人
傳私訊給我說我這裡沒有八個人
你有沒有更多人
但是我現在問題是台灣這邊沒有辦法玩
像我有一些香港玩家他們就會說
為什麼這一區的人都沒有
就是這個時間time zone的地方都沒有人
所以我那個時候我就target EU
就是Facebook ads
我就可以設定
EU的Player Bags
然後或是Google Apps
就是只好用這個方式去跟他們廣告
然後或者是說我就可能問他說
欸那在你那個國家裡面你們最常看的實況主是誰
我就會去想辦法去開發那個地方
因為畢竟他是當那邊的人
所以他可能會
很懂,像如果不是台灣的玩家的話,他們可能不知道我們最常用的平台是什麼
所以我就是只好用這樣的方式一步一步去慢慢做
就是可能不要太緊張,也不要太覺得說
啊,我們好像沒有辦法reach到他們
可是其實他們真的想玩的話,他們會找你
For playtesting, we used Steam, but we didn't do early access.
We used Steam only as the platform so that we can generate keys and give it to people,
and people trust Steam as a platform, and so we just used Steam.
But we would organize in Discord.
I mean, like...
Technically?
Not technically.
How do you observe the player action?
What do you do? And what feature is fun?
What feature is not? How do you determine these features?
A lot of fun has to do with balance.
If you have a game that requires balance,
like if you think League of Legends or our game, balance is very important.
You can add stats. Remember earlier I said game sparks.
Well, that's server-side.
So every time they play a game, at the end, I send stats to
our server.
Or you can use, a good website is Game Analytics.
Game Analytics is free.
And it's especially good for mobile sites.
They have a lot of extra stuff for mobile, if you do
something like that.
But any platform.
And from there, you can aggregate stats.
It'll show, like, you can calculate win-loss ratios with
a certain class.
You can calculate.
Does the average person have 50% wins or losses?
So you just have a bunch of stats,
and you send it to your server.
And again, you don't have to reinvent the wheel.
Use a platform that already does this for you.
In our case, GameSparks or Game Analytics.
We use both just in case there's discrepancy.
So you can compare.
我講的可能比較不專業,但是是跟玩家最直接接觸的
其實線上的酸民跟玩家是非常直接的
所以如果真的你的遊戲有不順或是不夠好或不好玩的地方
你馬上就會知道了,因為他們就會立刻來跟你抱怨
Never let me do complaints, this is not fun, please fix this
You will know
Yeah, we did internal playtest too.
What we did is we played with our moderators.
So we have community moderators, and maybe at the time
we had maybe like four or five.
And then we would also play with our Kickstarter backers
too to fill in some blanks.
And so whoever was there, we would invite,
because we didn't have that many people at the time.
And so we would just rally.
Scheduling was good too.
People from all different time zones wanted to play,
but it's really hard to get 8 to 16 people for our game.
It was really difficult.
So we would schedule persistent times.
And we had to have two separate ones.
There was no one perfect time.
So you have one that focuses on Europe,
and the other time that focuses on US.
And so we just did a survey to see what time
was the best for each one.
And so, in our case, we used, I think it was 9pm Eastern,
and, oh, I forgot the European one,
I'll have to get back to you, you can ask me later,
but it was split up in two different time zones
to make it persistent, and no plan for it.
So, did you do anything like physical,
face to face?
We did zero face-to-face playtesting.
Because, um...
Is it impossible?
No, it's not that it's impossible.
It's just, it's a lot of work, and it takes a lot of, um...
You know, we only have two programmers, so to us it's a lot of effort.
And we may have to...
If we wanted, like, a physical place to test, we'd have to pay.
And, you know, we didn't have any money to rent a place or anything like that.
And it would be sort of awkward if we just invite them to our home.
So...
Any other questions?
We have a question on the stream.
How do you decide how much you want for Kickstarter?
So to decide how much you want for Kickstarter,
If we're talking about what we did when we went for $20,000,
we thought that we want to calculate developer expenses.
We want to calculate enough for you to survive until launch.
And that's the biggest thing, because after your Kickstarter,
you do have to distribute to the team members, too.
You need some for yourself to survive
so that you can go full time.
And then you also need some for assets and further development.
Not everything will be free.
Like game servers, like Photon, for example, when we use that.
Once we started play testing, once you
go over a limit of maybe five people,
they'll start charging you.
And so you need to think when you want to launch.
And you calculate how long you'll
survive until you launch.
and then maybe plus an extra few months for buffer,
because you never know what extras you'll need.
There's always hidden stuff that you forgot about.
So you want more than what you expect.
For example, we thought it would take maybe about 15,000
to be perfect, ideal.
Ideally, we'd have 15,000.
So we went for the goal of 20,000,
so we have the extra 5,000.
buffer, so that just in case if something happens, then we're
covered.
We don't have to worry.
We never want to worry about it.
But how about how do you design different tiers of rewards?
OK, for different tiers of rewards, this is the hardest
part of a Kickstarter.
This takes a lot of work and effort.
So in our case, we had a shared Google Doc.
And we brought all of our team members in there.
And we're trying to
At first, you just come up with ideas.
So before you organize anything, just simply
put a whole bunch of ideas for what rewards we can give
and maybe some different money tiers.
So do we want to award people for $5?
In our case, we didn't give anything for $5.
$5 was just donation only.
So we put the minimum as $10.
buy one and get one free.
And yeah, you just have to dump all your ideas
in a shared document.
And then of those, move the good ideas
to a different section.
And then from there, you can decide what tier.
And then also, you have to think psychologically, too.
So you think, if someone's looking at a $10 tier,
if they look one down, are they encouraged to jump?
Are you encouraged to jump if you were a player looking at this?
If I saw $10 to $20 in my head, I think, that's double the price.
I don't know.
But, if you see $19, you're like, hmm, it's just a little bit more.
It's a psychology thing.
People are more likely to go to $19 than $20 when you're jumping from $10.
We have to think that way too.
We have to make sure that each tier they get a better deal than if they won less.
OK嗎?還是等他回覆比較快?
Hopefully that's OK.
We don't know if he's still on chat.
現場還有其他的問題嗎?還是大家還在想?
I'll ask a few questions. It's probably more about game design.
So, I think one of the unique feature or unique game mechanic in the game is that
you have a very powerful class like King.
So, I remember my second game.
I tried a game in my second game and I was assigned as...
And I think, I don't know, it's like, there's interesting that you have very powerful classes like that,
and you try to balance it out with all other classes.
But also it's kind of a stressful thing for new players to come in and have, you know,
play a sign of very important or very, like...
Critical role.
Yeah, or a very special role.
我會把這個問題解釋給觀眾聽
都要靠事後推理
然後很困難的地方是
這個國王
因為大家都知道他是國王
他是第一個被公開的作者
自動就會公開
然後這個國王通常都會很主動的
就是跟所有人要說
就是請所有人
跟我這個國王回報你的職業
那這個國王才能依序做他後續的動作
或者是說假如他是邪惡的國王的話
他要怎麼樣去害別人
但是我第一次玩的時候我就被
就更不方便了
We actually already have plans to split the modes into an easy mode, like a simple, you're
learning mode, and then the classic mode, which has everything.
And so we're also trying to restrict harder classes.
to new players.
So remember I said you should record stats?
One of the stats that we record is games played.
So now we can see, oh, you only played five games?
We're not going to randomly give you
the hardest class in the game.
And you may become that class through in-game mechanics,
but we're not going to start you as the hardest class ever.
Ends.
Yeah, that was definitely a mistake that we have learned.
And we're trying very hard to ramp the new player experience.
So I wish we would have done this a long time ago.
It's just, we just didn't have the resources at the time.
We could have, but instead we did different things.
So my advice to all of you guys is
think of, to pretend that you are a new player, or even.
get someone that's never played your game and watch them play
and ask them to think out loud.
Because it should be intuitive.
And they should know what to do on the first time playing.
And if they don't, then that's a problem
and it probably needs to be changed.
And in case of his question, he was one of the players
that made us, players like him made us realize, oh no,
we made a mistake.
We need to make, we need to.
make harder classes assigned to the veteran players.
So we need new classes,
the harder classes need to go to the people that have played tons of games.
They all know what to do.
But as for newer players, it may make them
freak out a little and run away.
They may think that all games are like this.
Let's say it was your first game, playing that,
as the hardest class in the game.
you may think that this whole game is like this and you're not going to play anymore.
You may have quit after your first game.
That's also about community engagement as well.
Because most of the players currently in the room
probably are experienced.
If you are assigned as a king, then people would
expect you to behave like a king.
Yeah, they are like, what are you doing?
I'm going to report you.
Yeah, that's the funny thing that happened.
Also, the players play as Prince, and he just killed everyone he jailed.
Yeah.
What we're going to do really soon is we're going to force a scripted tutorial.
And so it'll guide you through it, and it won't teach you the advanced classes, but...
if you do run into the advanced class, at least you have a concept of what to do.
Because a lot of people, like Elsa, she'll want to just skip the tutorial.
A tutorial will come up and say, this is the most important thing.
She'll go, skip.
So players don't like being forced into stuff like this.
But if you have a game where you have to be knowledgeable,
and it's a multiplayer game where it affects others, then.
If you 100% want to force a tutorial
Don't make it long, just enough to where they know the basics
You know, we have some buttons they can click for advance stuff
But we won't force the advance stuff on them, advance guides
But for the basics, force the tutorial, 100%
How long do you expect to continue maintaining and running the game?
Because it's an online game and
we have expectations.
This is one of those types of games
where people can play for a very long time and not get bored because of the replay value.
And so we expect it to go even longer than ten years.
So that's a big reason why
we decided to do online multiplayer.
is because we want that community, and we want them to keep playing for a very, very long time.
I think this game is like a board game that many people get in a room and play it.
So have you considered using VR?
Yeah, we actually have.
You know, you see games like Werewolves Within that has this sort of concept that you're physically in the same room with each other.
And, you know, we're definitely inspired by that. We do want to look into this one day.
It's definitely not our high priority list, but I'm a huge fan of HTC Vive, and I want one one day.
And this will be how I'll experiment.
We can start simple by just, you know, pop the UI out, make it so you can look around, instead of like a spinny camera.
HTC Vive
And it's...
I don't recommend it for like a game only with VR
Unless you have tons of money
But you know, adding VR support
I looked at some of the API documentation
It doesn't look very...
It doesn't look bad
It looks sort of easy to do
Easy as in like, you know, once you learn the basics anyway
小伙子有嗎?
有啦,我聽不懂
page in your presentation, you were talking about the
Steam page, the coming soon page, before you actually
opened up the store.
Because we know that Steam has a dedicated page view for new
titles, I remember there was like one million page views or
something, like the first.
First 30 days, they'll give you extra from launch.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
starting from launch or starting from?
It starts from launch.
So you can have it, don't be afraid to have your store early.
You can have it be as early as you want.
Once you launch, that's when you get the special 30 day
promotion where they'll push traffic to you.
And on top of that, oh, I guess NDA stuff, I can't say too
much about it, but in general, they'll promote you
every now and then.
有沒有其他問題?
有嗎?
有人其他問題嗎?
這邊好像有一個
Our marketing budget was about $200 per month, and so we spent that on Facebook.
We split it between Facebook and Google ads, and later on we tried some YouTube.
I really like the YouTube ads, if you have a decent trailer.
Our budget was really low for them.
But then post-launch, our budget is, we spend about $1,500
per month now for ads in the same things.
So Facebook, YouTube, Google Ads.
We're still investigating how much of an impact
it is because we only recently started
upping the budget for our ads.
So I can't tell you yet if it worked or not.
We're about to find an analyst to take a look at it,
make sure that it's doing something.
So yeah, if you plan to do ads,
find someone that can analyze it and make sure that it's working.
So you're not very sure about how much of a conversion rate you have right now?
We know that the click rate is pretty high.
That was the main point of the $200 a month for a while,
is you have to spend money at first to mold it the way you want to.
So you want a high click-through rate and very low click prices.
And that takes a while to get.
But now we have that, and that's where we're starting to experiment
and raise the budget.
And so you want a very high CTR, the click-through rate,
and that's sort of the best bang for the buck.
Do you have the next question here?
it's the best value you can get.
I don't recommend ads until
I don't recommend ads until way later.
I do recommend putting just a little bit into ads to try to get that
try to mess with the CTR and how much you pay per click
and try to, you know, that takes a little while to get perfect.
Facebook來的玩家,他們留的時間比較久,也比較,錯錯錯,我更正,Facebook來的玩家數量比較多,但是Google來的玩家,Google ads來的玩家留的比較久,所以他們的興趣是停留比較久的,但是Facebook可能只是,
一下下的
然後Facebook的廣告
如果你用Drift或是Video
是效益是比較高的
然後不要
不要在Twitter上
用廣告
Twitter廣告沒有很理想
然後YouTube是
我覺得YouTube Ad是
一定要做的
可是它不是在於說給多少人看到
而是在於你的那個view count
就是你這個video被人看過幾遍
那其實那個本身就是一個很好的廣告
不管他有沒有skip
有沒有就是跳把你的廣告按掉
其實它都是一個很好的投資
那其實我們個人是覺得廣告的現在的價錢很亂
然後又好像我們的budget其實沒有很高啦
那所以我們決定不要做
然後就是自己研究自己學
然後一開始真的就是很低
然後我們launch之後呢
其實他不知道因為廣告是我在負責
其實一個月大概有四千塊美金投資
然後最近我們發現說好像沒有
效益沒有那麼好
所以我們最近
就是不斷地慢慢提高
然後慢慢地去研究
而且你在研究的過程你也可以發現說
欸原來對你的東西有興趣的人是怎麼樣的
一開始我們以為我們不會有任何的女生玩家
但是在廣告的過程當中你發現
欸其實我們有18%都是女生玩家
然後所以你可以從你剩下的錢
就是你所有生活完了
然後你有一些閒錢
你就全部投資在廣告商
然後再越早開始做越好
因為你越早開始做
你就知道你要怎麼target他們
然後他們有興趣的是誰
而且有的廣告商很好是
你可以target你的競爭對手
就例如說全家的廣告
但是他target的是7-11的
的消費族群
那其實這是一個很好的方法
就是你可以去找類似的
或者是說我可以target桌遊
因為我們遊戲本身非常的難
那我就會target說
那可能是桌遊的人才會來玩我們
如果是射擊遊戲的可能對我們一點興趣都沒有
那相對你在找實況主的時候
也是要找
如果他只玩射擊遊戲
你就不要期待他會不會你的信
之類的
就是從一開始就要開始研究那個
那個 對 但是我講回來就是
廣告的預算確實是一條路
但是你可以慢慢增加 慢慢增加
從你可以接受的範圍 然後慢慢到很高
但是我們最近調到最高了 可是我們卻決定要停下來
先檢查一下是不是真的有那個效益這樣子
不好意思
請問一下你剛剛講的廣告
沒關係 沒關係
好 這應該夠了
那我想請問一下你剛剛講的廣告是有針對像是美國區域
台灣區域或者是日本區
或者是你的廣告就是全球性的
我的廣告一開始我針對所有英語國家
就是說英語的國家
所以才會有香港的人來跟我抱怨說
欸怎麼沒有人玩
然後我說可是因為我們不是中文版啊
然後當有人跟我說
欸,EU這邊都沒有人玩
然後我就會去強化
就是可能例如說我可能100塊放美國
然後50塊放EU
那這個時候我就會調一下
可能這邊就放更多
這邊就先放150,先放個幾天
就拉一些EU的玩家進來
然後實況主的影響力非常的大
因為我們有一個實況主他是玩Hearthstone
盧斯
他是玩盧斯的
然後他住在芬蘭
然後他一玩之後我們
我就去看我們的那個Player
然後就想說奇怪我們芬蘭怎麼這麼多人
因為我沒有在芬蘭打任何廣告
然後原來就想到說
啊是因為他是芬蘭人
所以他的
可能他那邊的國家的人
然後之後我們有一個版主
就是我們discord裡面有一個
就是我們討論區的一個版主
他是挪威人
我們就發現有越來越多的挪威人進來
然後那些就是我完全沒有去搭廣告的
可是也因為他們我就會覺得說
欸那我要照顧他們
所以我就會可能再分個20塊
就是我能夠有的錢我就分個20塊到挪威
就算說一天可能只有5個人看到
10個人看到也好這樣
所以
如果你是英文的然後又是online的
又是在Steam的話
真的要去考慮
你的世界要去考慮全世界的問題對
那你就可以
可能要去分配
那一開始你可能可以先打主力
美國或是你覺得
某個國家你特別喜歡
就是它是整個實驗的過程
那隨時都可以微調
就是你的廣告隨時都可以去調整
我要target哪裡
我要target幾歲
我要target男生女生這樣子
那你們在選擇上
想怎麼講
像是一開始是沒有投預算在芬蘭的
那可能一開始可能是美國人比較多
那你們為什麼是選擇就是讓預算平衡一點
而不是變成乾脆就全部都投美國
讓大的跟小的就放棄
我只是好奇
懂我的意思嗎
我懂呃
其實一開始真的沒有想那麼多
就是
反正想說
好像有打廣告應該就會有一些
但是你一定會遇到
就是隨著你慢慢
遊戲慢慢成長
你一定會遇到不一樣的問題
所以我之後才會開始微調
所以一開始我就沒有去特別想說
我要針對哪個國家
我就想說 反正我就 因為那個時候我也是新手
就是 然後我又沒辦法花那麼多錢去打廣告
所以我想說 那一天六百塊先試看看
所以六百塊其實你不能 你不能說
你就算打美國也是打很小的一點
然後你打全世界可能也完全沒有效益
所以我覺得我能夠怎麼做
我當下能夠怎麼做 我就先怎麼做
那其實我覺得這是對於所有獨立開發者一個很好的
就是你能夠做多少你就先去做多少
然後當你開始有一點成就的成績的時候
你身邊的人自然會就是越來越幫你
那你遇到什麼困難你就再解決
而且線上的支援很多
對我每次遇到廣告問題我就是
線上線Google就是都是Google大神對謝謝
It seems like streamer is more effective than ad.
So you just said that streamer get free game everyday, a bunch of free game everyday.
So how do you stand out for those streamer?
我最近發現就是YouTube已經有點pass了
Twitch是Future
對 因為我一開始
他都在開發
那我就要負責就是
推廣的部分
然後我就是先蒐集list
就是先在Google上面
那有一些網路上
一定會有一些就是已經蒐集好的
然後我又加上我自己的
因為每個遊戲不同嘛 所以target有不同
所以我就每天就是蒐集資料
然後蒐集他們的email
然後
你就只能email給他們
然後我們找到了幾個不錯的
就是他原本是我們競爭對手
Used to stream Tower7
他原本是我們競爭對手
他們想說我們最近有個新出來的遊戲
你要不要玩玩看
那有幾個真的跳過來開始玩我們的
然後但是他們開始玩的時候
你就要注意是不是真的有帶入一些效益或是收益
然後我們發現
就是 雖然實況主是真的很強
然後真的很有影響力
可是也因為不同的人經營
然後跟不同的平台有不一樣的反應跟效益
所以一開始我們在Alpha跟Beta的時候
我就只focus在YouTube
因為YouTube真的我要去接觸的實況主已經太多了
然後沒有帶入任何效益
但是我們
Launch了之後就開始有Twitch的人玩
然後Twitch就是他們只要玩我們就一定有收益
玩我們就一定有收益
可是也是因為我們遊戲的本質
因為我們遊戲本質是所有
所以是互動性很高的
所以也許你的遊戲會不一樣
就是 但是通常我們自己啦
我們自己到YouTube
我們如果看一個YouTube影片
其實我們自己好像也不會去
我們就單純只是看影片而已
可是當我們去Twitch的時候
可能就是真的會去下單
或者是說真的會去買東西
所以
如果說你真的要target
實況主的話
可以往Twitch那邊找
那YouTube就可以
可能就是放30%或20%
你的心力去
經營就好
we can promote the Twitch streamers very well because
when they go online we can announce through
whatever platform you use, in our case Discord, we can announce that
these guys are going online, go check them out. We can tweet them, we can say, hey
this guy's going online, sub sub sub.
It really is sort of a win-win situation. They'll get
followers, they'll get subscriptions, they'll get viewers.
And at the same time, they're playing our game.
So it's a win for everybody.
And then as indie developers, you can make extensions to
even, I mentioned earlier, you can push
engagement even more.
And a lot of streamers just keep requesting that we add
tools to help them.
Because the more that you can engage with
这些Twitch的直播者,观众更想看到,观众更想参与,而不是只看
这就是Twitch的特色,它是在发展的
以前只是一个让你看一个游戏,但是现在是在与游戏和直播者一起参与
这真的帮助了,这比任何你买的广告都好
那我覺得就這樣
如果還有別的問題的話
就是如果你要私下單獨問
就直接等一下來前面跟講者來討論
這樣就OK
那我們最後再掌聲感謝
李先生